Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.2
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-pro",
"thinking_budget": 24576,
"max_subtitle_chars": 60,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING ACCURACY (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry are meticulously accurate.** Both must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and end of the spoken words* for that specific segment.
*   **CRITICAL: The `end` timestamp is frequently inaccurate and requires special attention.** It must precisely mark the *exact conclusion* of the spoken content for that subtitle entry.
*   Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **CRITICAL: Holistic Translation, Contextual Understanding & Comprehensive Analysis:**
*   **You ABSOLUTELY MUST watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative.
*   **When a single logical sentence or phrase is split across multiple subtitle entries (e.g., due to timing or character limits), you MUST mentally combine these parts to understand the full, complete meaning before translating.**
*   **NEVER translate individual subtitle entries in isolation if they are part of a larger, continuous thought or sentence.** The translation for each entry must be a coherent and accurate part of the complete, overarching sentence.
*   Analyze *all* spoken dialogue in the video to produce highly accurate and complete transcriptions.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If the audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals from the video, surrounding dialogue) to infer and generate the most probable dialogue.
*   Utilize the comprehensive understanding gained from *watching the entire video* to enhance the accuracy of transcriptions, translations, and overall subtitle quality. This includes understanding nuances, resolving ambiguities, and ensuring the subtitle content aligns perfectly with what is happening visually.
*   **Example:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **Dual Language Provision & Translation Quality:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue.
*   If the original dialogue is in English, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding Japanese translation.
*   If the original dialogue is in Japanese, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding English translation.
*   Ensure translations are culturally appropriate and maintain the original meaning, tone, and intent, taking into account the full context of the video and any split sentences.
4.  **Readability & Formatting:**
* Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Each subtitle entry (english and japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters. Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
* Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
鷹嶺ルイ 生誕祭 2025「MUSIC GARDEN」
TAKANE LUI Birthday 2025: MUSIC GARDEN
2025年6月11日(水) 20:00〜 Lui Ch.にて
2025.6.11 WED 20:00 on Lui Ch.
重大告知あり!!
Major Announcement!!
ミュージックガーデン！
Music Garden!
鷹嶺ルイ バースデーライブ 2025！
Takane Lui Birthday Live 2025!
はい、尾丸ポルカです。よろしくお願いします。
Hi, I'm Omaru Polka. A pleasure to be here.
こんばんは。司会の白上フブキです。
Good evening. I'm your host, Shirakami Fubuki.
よろしくお願いします。
It's great to be here.
さて、今夜も始まりましたミュージックガーデンでございますけども
Well then, tonight's Music Garden has now begun...
なんか久々だね。
It's been a while, hasn't it?
はい、約2年ぶりに復活ということでですね。
Yes, it's making a comeback after about two years.
あ、復活！や、めでたいね！
Oh, a comeback! How celebratory!
そうですね！
It is!
髪切った？
Did you get a haircut?
あ、いや、切ってないんですけども、2年前もそんなこと言ってましたね。
Oh, no, I didn't. You said the same thing two years ago.
そうだっけ？
Did I?
そうですよ！ポルさんもお変わりなく。
Yes, you did! And you haven't changed a bit, Polka.
ま、はい。元気でやってます。
Well, yes. I'm doing great.
それはよかったです。
That's good to hear.
ポルさんの元気に負けないくらい、今回元気なゲストさんもいますので。
And we have guests today who are just as energetic as you are.
んー、それは楽しみだね。
Hmm, that's exciting.
はい。では早速紹介していきましょうか。
Yes. So shall we introduce them right away?
本日のゲストの登場です！
Here are today's guests!
音乃瀬奏！
Otonose Kanade!
猫又おかゆ！
Nekomata Okayu!
大神ミオ！
Ookami Mio!
百鬼あやめ！
Nakiri Ayame!
鷹嶺ルイ！
Takane Lui!
今夜も豪華ゲストでお送りするミュージックガーデン。
Tonight's Music Garden is brought to you by a lineup of amazing guests.
なんと今夜はあっと驚くような仕掛けいっぱいでお送りするみたいですよ。
And tonight, it looks like we have a lot of surprising gimmicks for you.
最後まで見逃せません！
You won't want to miss a thing until the very end!
ああ…どんな仕掛けなんだろうねえ…
Ah... I wonder what kind of gimmicks there are...
えー、鷹嶺ルイくん。
Well, Takane Lui-kun.
はい。
Yes.
ミュージックガーデンといえば、まあ鷹嶺ルイくんだから。
Speaking of Music Garden, it's all about you, Takane Lui-kun.
今日は誕生日ということで。
And today is your birthday.
はい。
Yes.
ありがとうございます。そうなんですよ。今日誕生日なんですよ。
Thank you. That's right. Today's my birthday.
ふあー、何年ぶりに復活したけど
Wow, it's been a few years since its revival, but...
え、どう？緊張してる？
So, how is it? Are you nervous?
うん、緊張してます。
Yes, I'm nervous.
でも復活にふさわしい場にできるんじゃないかなと思っているので、楽しみにしててください。
But I think we can make this a fitting event for the revival, so please look forward to it.
復活…これなんか匂いますね。
Revival... I smell something about this.
え？ちゃんと、お風呂入ってきた？
What? Did you take a proper bath?
え、その匂いじゃ、違いますね。それじゃないですよ。
Uh, that's not the kind of smell I mean. Not that one.
あ、そっかそっか。
Oh, right, right.
今日は1曲目の披露だよね？
You're performing the first song today, right?
はい、この後すぐに披露させていただきます。
Yes, I'll be performing right after this.
はい、1曲目は鷹嶺ルイさんにアニメの主題歌でも話題でした
Yes, for the first song, Takane Lui-san will be performing the theme song from that popular anime,
「BOW AND ARROW」を披露していただきます。
'BOW AND ARROW'.
おお、あのフィギュアスケートの。
Oh, the one from that figure skating anime.
はい。今回は特別にフィギュアスケート風のダンスを
Yes. This time, I have a special figure skating-style dance
踊ってくださるダンサーさんと一緒にパフォーマンスさせていただきます。
and I'll be performing with the dancers.
【このあと「BOW AND ARROW」披露 フィギュアスケートイメージのダンスにも注目！】
[Performing 'BOW AND ARROW' next. Pay attention to the figure skating-inspired dance!]
うわー！
Whoa!
そりゃあ楽しみだなあ。
I'm really looking forward to that.
そうですね。それではスタンバイの方よろしくお願いします。
Indeed. Well then, please get ready to go on standby.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, will do.
ねえ、あれ、猫又くんと音乃瀬くんと大神くん、
Hey, isn't it Nekomata-kun, Otonose-kun, and Ookami-kun's...
あ、初登場だっけ？
...ah, first appearance?
そうですー！
That's right!
初登場！はい！
First appearance! Yes!
うーん、音乃瀬くん緊張してるんじゃない？
Hmm, aren't you nervous, Otonose-kun?
もう全然大丈夫です！
Not at all, I'm totally fine!
行けます！
I can do this!
おお！おぉ…
Whoa! Oh...
元気だね。
So energetic.
行くぞよー！
Let's gooo!
そして2回目の登場が百鬼くん。
And making her second appearance is Nakiri-kun.
はい、お久しぶりです。
Yes, it's been a while.
今日シュークリーム食べた？
Did you eat a cream puff today?
え、ちょっと今日はまだ、まだ今日は食べてないです。
Uh, not yet, I haven't eaten one today.
あ、はい。ふふふ。
Ah, I see. (laughs)
あ、そうかそうかそうか。
Oh, I see, I see.
じゃ後でね、ゆっくりね、
Well then, later, take your time,
はい、いっぱい食べます。
Yes, I'll eat lots of them.
食べてね。はい。
Make sure you do. I will.
え、後ほど皆さんとゆっくりお話しさせていただこうと思います。
Well, we'll talk more with everyone later.
さて、スタンバイができたみたいですね
Well, it looks like they're ready to go.
アニメをリスペクトしたダンスにもご注目ください
Please also pay attention to the anime-inspired dance.
鷹嶺ルイで、BOW AND ARROW
This is Takane Lui with "BOW AND ARROW."
気づけば靴は汚れ
I realized my shoes were dirty,
錆びついた諸刃を伝う雨
rain runs down the rusty double-edged sword.
憧れはそのまままで
My yearning remains as it is,
夢から目醒めた先には夢
and beyond waking from a dream is another dream.
聞こえたその泣き声
I heard that crying voice,
消え入る手前の咽びソワレ
a choked-up soirée right before fading away.
憧れのその先へ
Beyond that yearning,
蹲る君を見つける為
to find you, crouching there.
行け 行け 追いつけない速度で
Go, go, at an unreachable speed,
飛べ インパルス加速して
fly, accelerating the impulse.
行け きっとこの時を感じる為に
Go, surely to feel this moment,
生まれてきたんだ
I was born.
未来を掴んで 期待値を超えて
Seize the future, exceed expectations,
頬に吹き刺す風
the wind that pierces my cheek.
今に見なよ
Just you watch,
きっと君の眩しさに誰もが気づくだろう
everyone will surely notice your radiance.
相応しい声で 視線追い越して
With a worthy voice, outpace their gazes,
虚空を超えて行け
go beyond the void.
見違えていく君の指から今
From your transforming fingers, now,
手を放す
I let go of your hand.
気づけば謎は解かれ
I realized the mystery was solved,
木目ごと見慣れた板の上
on the familiar board, grain and all.
あの頃焦がれたような
I wonder if I've become the adult
大人になれたかな
I yearned to be back then.
そう君の苦悩は君が自分で選んだ痛みだ
Yes, your anguish is the pain you chose for yourself.
そして掴んだあの煌めきも
And that sparkle you grasped,
全て君のものだ
is all yours.
僕は弓になって
I became a bow,
君の白んだ掌をとって強く引いた
took your pale hand and pulled it back hard.
今君は決して風に流れない
Now, you've become an arrow that will never be swayed
矢になって
by the wind.
行け 行け 決して振り向かないで
Go, go, never look back,
飛べ もう届かない場所へ
fly, to a place you can no longer reach.
行け 行け 行け
Go, go, go!
君はいつだって輝いていた！
You were always shining!
未来を掴んで 期待値を超えて
Seize the future, exceed expectations,
頬に吹き刺す風
the wind that pierces my cheek.
今に見なよ
Just you watch,
きっと君の眩しさに誰もが気づくだろう
everyone will surely notice your radiance.
相応しい声で 視線追い越して
With a worthy voice, outpace their gazes,
虚空を超えて行け
go beyond the void.
見違えていく君の指から今
From your transforming fingers, now,
手を放す
I let go of your hand.
I let go.
はい、続いてはねこたかです。
Okay, next up is Nekotaka.
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you.
2人はどういう関係なの？
What's the relationship between you two?
パーティー仲間で。
Party buddies.
パーティー？
Party?
はい。
Yes.
よくルイの家で勝手にパーティー開催してます。
We often hold parties at Lui's house without her permission.
勝手に？
Without permission?
まあなかなか、仲が良くてもですね、人の家で勝手にパーティー
Well, even if you're close, you shouldn't just party.
いやいや、そうなんですけど、最初私もね、すごい驚いたんですが、
No, no, that's true, and I was surprised at first...
最近ではね、もう私から「次いつパーティー？」って言うくらいにはね、虜になっちゃってますね。
but lately I'm the one asking, "When's the next party?" I'm captivated.
うわー。
Wow...
ああ、これ、猫又くんの策略かな。
Ah, is this Nekomata-kun's strategy?
こうなると思ってました。
I thought this would happen.
思ってたんだ。
You thought so.
ポルさんも今度どうですか、パーティー。
Pol-san, how about you join the party next time?
パーティーっていうのは、私も行っていいのかな？
A party? Is it okay for me to go too?
是非是非。
Of course, of course.
ぜひぜひ。
Yes, please.
あ、やっぱり猫又くんが許可出すんだね。
Ah, so Nekomata-kun is the one giving permission.
ねえ、楽しそうですね。
Yeah, it sounds fun, doesn't it?
フブさんも是非。
Fubu-san, you too, please.
ええ？
Huh?
あ、じゃあ、この後とかにも行きましょうか？ポルさん、ねぇ？
Oh, then shall we go after this? Pol-san, right?
もうね、これ、鷹嶺くんが苦笑いしてるんですけど、なんか勝手に寝だされちゃいましたね。
You know, Takane-kun is giving a wry smile, but she got roped in.
ですけども、まあ、そんなお二人にはですね、かっこよさが詰まったダークチックな曲を披露していただきます。
But anyway, for these two, they'll perform a cool, dark and chic song.
闇営業してるじゃないか。
It's like they're working on the side.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
でもね、あの、ねこたかならではの低音を活かしたかっこいいパフォーマンスをしますので、
But, we'll give a cool performance that makes use of Nekotaka's low tones,
楽しみにしててください。
so please look forward to it.
はい！じゃ、それではスタンバイお願いします。
Okay! Then, please get on standby.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Okay, please take care of us.
お願いします。
Please do.
いやー、仲がよろしいようでいいですね。
Wow, it's nice that they get along so well.
まあ、ぶっちゃけあれは鷹嶺くんもまんざらでもなさそうだよね。
Well, to be honest, it doesn't seem like Takane-kun minds it either.
ねぇ、そうですね。なんか我々もパーティーに混ざっていいみたいですから。
Right? It seems we can join the party too.
なんかあの、ルイさんの作るポテトサラダが絶品らしいのでね。
Apparently, the potato salad Lui-san makes is exquisite.
お、なんか詳しいね。
Oh, you seem to know a lot.
あ、まあまあまあまあまあまあ、あ、ということで、スタンバイができたみたいですね。
Ah, well, well... anyway, it looks like they're ready.
え、なんか隠し事？
Huh? Are you hiding something?
あ、いえいえいえいえいえいえ
Ah, no, no, no, no.
え、それでは参りましょう。ねこたかでフィクサー。
Well then, let's begin. Nekotaka with "Fixer."
今日までの記憶の全部を消してしまう時まで眠れない
I can't sleep until I've erased all my memories up to today
明日から生きてく自分の身代わりが欲しくて堪らない
I desperately want a substitute to live for me from tomorrow
大丈夫と言わせて　後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
Let me say "it's okay", and then won't you let me blame it on you later?
今更意味ないから後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
It's meaningless now, so can't you just let me blame you later?
出来ない約束をとうとうと溢れる一言一言ばかりに脳を奪われるくらい
My mind is nearly stolen by glibly spoken, impossible promises.
意味を成せない 何も出来ない
I can't make any sense of it. I can't do anything.
見えない 逃げたい 飛びたい やめたい 逸らせない
Can't see, wanna run, wanna fly, wanna stop, can't look away.
だから
So then,
沈め沈め 這い上がれないほどまで
Sink, just sink, until you can no longer crawl back up.
飽きるまで落とせ落とせ 救い垂らす時まで
Until you're sick of it, fall, fall, till salvation comes.
嘘味の粒々を喉から絞め出した悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
I'll crush the lie-flavored specks and the scream they're from.
笑顔が下手なばっかで 知ったような口ぶりに沿ってやり過ごす
Just because I'm bad at smiling, I get by with a know-it-all tone.
なりたくなかった
I didn't want to become this.
今日役立つ眠たい眠たい理想で救われることを待つ
Today I wait to be saved by this useful, sleepy, sleepy ideal.
一番目は「い」の口で言う
The first is said with the shape of an "i" mouth.
力強く固く痛く噛み締めて
Clenching down forcefully, firmly, painfully,
死んでしまえ
Just go and die.
この先も過去も知らず
Go on, ignorant of the future and past.
嫌いなら
If you hate it,
壊せ壊せ どうせなら加害者になればいい
break it, break it. It's fine if I just become the villain.
食べきれない苛立ちも何も生まない悲しみも
Both the unbearable irritation and the fruitless sorrow,
味気なくて吐き出す前にもう もう次を歌え
before I spit out this tasteless thing, go on and sing the next.
沈め沈め
Sink, just sink...
落とせ落とせ
Fall, just fall...
どうせなら踊り踊れ 眠り落ちる時まで
If you must, dance, just dance, till you fall asleep.
灰色になりきる前に 打ち鳴らせ
Before you turn to grey, make some noise.
変われ変われ 眠り落ちる時まで
Change, just change. Until the moment you fall asleep.
どうせなら奪え奪え 飼い慣らした嘘暴いて
If you must, take, just take, and expose the tamed lies.
煮え滾る頭によぎった虚像を見ていた
I was watching the false image that crossed my boiling mind.
自分を見ていた
I was watching myself.
続いてはルイなでのお二人です。
Next up, it's the duo "Luina de".
よろしくお願いします！
It's a pleasure to be here!
元気いいね。
So energetic.
また言ってるんだよ。
There you go again.
お二人は先輩と後輩なんだよね。
You two are a senpai-kouhai pair, right?
じゃあ、よく話すの？
So, do you talk a lot?
はい、よくご飯に行ったりします。
Yes, we often go out to eat.
お、ご飯。
Oh, meals.
いいね。
Nice.
何食べるの？
What do you eat?
まあ、主にしゃぶしゃぶですかね。
Well, mainly shabu-shabu, I guess.
しゃぶしゃぶか。
Shabu-shabu, huh?
一緒の鍋をつつく関係、まあこれいいね。
A relationship where you share a hotpot. That's nice.
え、実は、え、今日ポルさんにご相談がありまして。
Uhm, actually, today I have something I'd like to ask you, Pol-san.
相談？
Ask me?
ルイ先輩はいつまでたってもね、奏のお母さんにはなってくれないんですよ。
No matter how much time passes, Lui-senpai won't become my mother.
お母さん？
Mother?
言ってやってくださいよ。
Tell her off.
先輩お母さんにするの？
You want your senpai to be your mom?
もちろん、もちろん。奏はいつでも優しいお母さんになってくださる方々を募集してます。
Of course. I'm always looking for people who will be a kind mother to me.
よろしくお願いします。
Please let me know.
なんでお母さんになってあげないの？逆に。
Then why won't you be her mom?
いや、なんか奏は娘って感じがしないというか
Well, it's not that Kanade doesn't feel like a daughter, but...
娘になったらなんか手が掛かりすぎて、責任が持てないなって感じなので、親戚ポジションでいいかなって感じですね。
if she were my daughter, she'd be too much of a handful. I couldn't take responsibility, so I think a relative's position is fine.
結構な相談だな。
That's quite the thing to ask.
音乃瀬君はじゃあ、他にもママがいるの？
So, Otonose-kun, do you have other moms?
もちろん、もちろん。
Of course, of course.
じゃ、いらないでしょ。
Then you don't need one.
なんで欲しいの？
Why do you want one?
え、それはね、頼れる人はいっぱいいた方がいいじゃないですか。
Well, it's better to have lots of people to rely on, isn't it?
え、じゃあ、逆にポルさん、奏のお父さんになってくれませんか？
Then, on the flip side, Pol-san, would you be my father?
え？お父さん？
Huh? Father?
お父さん？
Father?
どうですか？
How about it?
その意見は父さん(倒産)って言ってなあ。
That opinion is bankrupt (tousan)!
えー、ではですね、ルイなでにはこの後、名前のない怪物を披露していただきます。
Alright then, Luina de will now perform "The Nameless Monster" for us.
なんでこの曲選んだ？
Why did you choose this song?
すぐ、すぐ行けるんだ、そうやって。
You can just move on like that, huh?
え、私がですね、EGOISTが大好きで
Well, I love EGOIST,
その中でもこの曲がすごい大好きなんですけど、奏の初めての歌ってみたがこの曲で、いつか一緒に歌いたいなと思ってこの曲にしました。
and I really love this song. Kanade's first cover was this song, and I wanted to sing it with her someday.
うぷ、嬉しい。
Oh, I'm so happy.
え、それではですね、お二人ともスタンバイお願いします。
Alright then, if you two would please get ready.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, thank you very much.
なんかはちゃめちゃな子だね。
She's kind of a chaotic kid, huh?
はい、ですね。なんかよく月曜日に現実を突きつけたりしてるみたいですよ。
Yes, she is. Apparently, she often forces reality upon people on Mondays.
ああ、罪深い。
Ah, how sinful.
クソガキだ。
What a brat.
クソガキですね。はい。
She's a brat, yes.
ま、しかし歌で見せてくれるので、ギャップ萌えしてる人も多いんじゃないかなと思います。
But she sings so well, so I think a lot of people experience 'gap moe' from her.
鷹嶺くんも歌うとかっこいいのに、なんかポンコツだからね。
Takane-kun is also cool when she sings, but she's kind of a klutz.
そうですね。ま、ギャップがある二人って感じじゃないでしょうかね。
That's right. They're a duo with a 'gap,' wouldn't you say?
はい、じゃあ、それでは参りましょう。ルイなでで、名前のない怪物。
Okay, then let's begin. From Luina de, "The Nameless Monster."
名前のない怪物
The Nameless Monster
御伽話は
The fairy tale
さっき死んだみたい
seems to have just died.
煉瓦の病棟でうまく歌えなくて
In the brick ward, I couldn't sing well.
霧に煙る夜 浮かべ赤い月
On a foggy night, a red moon floats.
ほらみて 私を
Hey, look at me.
目を逸らさないで
Don't look away.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside black iron bars,
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born.
悪意の代償を願え
Wish for the price of malice,
望むがままにお前に
just as you desire, for you.
さあ与えよう正義を
Now, I shall grant you justice.
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy, before you are destroyed.
因果の代償を払い
Pay the price of karma,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがしてる
My ears are ringing.
鉄条網うるさくって
The barbed wire is so noisy.
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember the melody of that day.
雨はまだ止まない
The rain still hasn't stopped.
何にも見えないの
I can't see anything.
ほらみて こんなに大きくなったの
Look, I've grown so big now.
黒い雨 降らせこの空
Black rain, fall from this sky.
私は望まれないもの
I am something unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis.
愛す同罪の傍観者達に
To the bystanders who love the same crime.
さあ今ふるえる正義を
Now, this trembling justice,
消せない傷を抱きしめて
embrace the indelible scar.
この身体を受け入れ
Accept this body,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, nameless monster.
ああ
Ah
神は告げる
God proclaims...
真の世界を
...the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside these black iron bars,
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born.
悪意の代償を願え
Pray for the price of malice,
望むがままにお前に
as you wish, to you.
さあ与えよう正義を
Now, I'll give you justice.
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy, before you are destroyed.
因果の代償を払い
Pay the price of karma,
報いよ 名もなき怪物
receive your due, nameless monster.
黒い雨 降らせこの空
Let the black rain fall from this sky.
私は望まれないもの
I am something unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis.
愛す同罪の傍観者達に
To the complicit bystanders I love.
さあ今ふるえ正義を
Now, brandish your justice.
消せない傷を抱きしめて
Embrace the indelible scars.
この身体を受け入れ 共にいこう
Accept this body, let's go together,
名前のない怪物
nameless monster.
さて、ここからは...
Now, from here on...
楠木ともりが鷹嶺ルイ生誕記念グッズ2025をご紹介。
Tomori Kusunoki will introduce Takane Lui's 2025 Birthday Goods.
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド。
Glitter Acrylic Stand.
キラキラなラメ入りアクリルスタンドが、とってもおしゃれな一品。
This sparkling glitter acrylic stand is a very stylish item.
光を浴びるたびに、きめ細かなラメがキラキラと輝きを放ちます。
Each time it catches the light, fine glitter sparkles brilliantly.
光り輝くアクリルスタンドで、あなたの生活も更に明るくなるでしょう。
With this radiant acrylic stand, your life will surely become even brighter.
ロック風パーカー。
Rock-style Hoodie.
イベントやライブで着るだけでなく、日常にも溶け込むロック風パーカー。
Not just for events or concerts, this hoodie also fits into everyday life.
前にジップがついているので、部屋着でも普段着でも使いやすい。
With a zipper in the front, it's easy to use as loungewear or casual wear.
部屋着でも普段着でも使いやすい
It's easy to wear as loungewear or everyday wear.
ヘビロテ間違いなし!!
You'll definitely wear it all the time!
ゆるかわバケットハット
Cute & Casual Bucket Hat
つくねとつみれがワンポイントになっていて
Tsukune and Tsumire are the accent point,
シンプルおしゃかわ
making it simply stylish and cute.
普段使いしやすいデザインで
With a design that's easy for everyday use,
手軽におしゃれ度UP
you can effortlessly level up your style.
カジュアル、ストリート、古着MIX、
It matches casual, street, and vintage mix styles,
きれいめカジュアルの外しアイテムなど、幅広いスタイルにマッチ
and as an accent for smart casual outfits.
「え？」Tシャツ
"Eh?" T-shirt
ルイーシュでおなじみのセリフ「え？」をモチーフに
The familiar "Eh?" phrase from Lui-shu is the motif
ネタTとして堂々発売
for this grand release of a novelty T-shirt.
どんなコーディネートにも合う白で
The white color matches any outfit.
夏は単体で、冬はパーカーと合わせてインナーとして、
Wear it in summer, or with a hoodie in winter.
一年を通して使えます。
You can use it all year round.
全部セットは数量限定もアリ！
The full set is also available in limited quantities!
鷹嶺ルイ直筆サイン
Bonus: A postcard with Takane Lui's autograph
＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード特典
& a hot-stamped replica message.
hololive 公式ECサイトへ急げ！！
Hurry to the hololive official online store!!
今だけ！！！
For a limited time!!!
誕生日記念のフルセットを1点購入につき、hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PRカード1枚プレゼント！！！
For each purchase of the Birthday Commemorative Full Set, you'll receive one hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PR card as a gift!!!
続いてはミオルイです。
Next up is MioRui.
よろしくお願いします。
Please welcome us.
お願いします。
なかなかな、この2人っていうのは珍しいよね。
This is quite a rare pairing, isn't it?
そうですね。
Is that so?
結構ね、あのお話はしたり仲いいんですよ。
We actually talk quite a bit and get along well.
はい、そうなんです。
Yes, we do.
うーん、何について話してる？
Hmm, what do you talk about?
ええ、主に、まあ、私がそもそもミオしゃの歌が本当に大好きで
Well, mainly, I really, really love Mio-sha's singing,
よく歌のお話をしたりとか、
so we often talk about singing,
あとは個人的に私の悩みを聞いてもらったりとか
and she also listens to my personal worries.
してますね。
はーい。たよりがいがあるからね。
I see. She's so reliable.
なんかその、特別なエピソードとかあったりする？
So, do you have any special episodes or anything?
特別なエピソードでいうと、私がちょっとしょぼんとした時があったんですけど、
Speaking of special episodes, there was a time I was feeling a bit down,
その時にパーティーを開いてくれまして。
and she threw a party for me.
あ、例のね。うん。
Ah, that one. Right.
その時にミオしゃが花束をプレゼントしてくれたんですよ。
At that time, Mio-sha gave me a bouquet of flowers as a gift.
ああ、覚えてる覚えてる。
Ah, I remember, I remember.
ルイの色のね、花束をね。
A bouquet in Lui's colors, right?
そう。ルイカラーのね
Yes, a Lui-colored...
あの花束をプレゼントしてくれて、
She gave me that bouquet,
それがすごくきれいで、曇ってた心が瞬にして晴れましたね。
and it was so beautiful that my cloudy feelings cleared up in an instant.
はい。
Yes.
ああ、素敵だね。
Aww, that's lovely.
大神さんはよく花とか買うの？
Ookami-san, do you often buy things like flowers?
あ、はい、あのお花すごい大好きで、
Ah, yes, I love flowers.
あの、うちも落ち込んだ時とかね、あのお花を買うとき結構あるんですけど
I also often buy flowers when I'm feeling down, but...
猫が食べちゃうんで、まああんまり買えないんですけどね。
my cats eat them, so I can't really buy them that often.
そうですね、猫ね。
That's right, the cats.
さっき聞き逃してたけど、君たちもよくパーティーするんだね。
I missed it earlier, but you guys have parties often too, huh?
あ、そうですね。まあ、でもお粥と同じパーティーです。
Ah, yes. Well, it's the same party as Okayu's.
はい。
Yes.
あ、そうです。あの私もよく実は参加させていただいております。
Ah, yes. I actually participate often, too.
さっき隠してたのって、白上君も参加してるってこと？
You were hiding it earlier, but does that mean you participate too, Shirakami-kun?
あ、そうですね、あの、
Ah, yes.
みおさんのオムライスとルイさんのポテトサラダはもう本当にめちゃめちゃ絶品なんですよ。
Mio-san's omurice and Lui-san's potato salad are absolutely exquisite.
おいしいよね。
They're delicious.
いや、ちょっと収集つかなくなりそうなんで、スタンバイお願いします。
Okay, this is getting out of hand, so please get on standby.
はい。よろしくお願いします。またパーティーしようね。
Okay. See you later. Let's have another party soon.
パーティー、パーティー、パーティー。
Party, party, party.
白上君も
Shirakami-kun too.
ああ、なんか作ったりしてるの？パーティーで。
Ah, do you make anything for the party?
いや、私はあの食べる専門ですね。
No, I'm the one who specializes in eating.
食べる専門。ああ、甘やかされてるね。
Specializing in eating. Ah, you're so spoiled.
そうですね。ポルさんも一度いかがですか？
That's right. How about you join in once, Poru-san?
うんうん。
Uh-huh.
うん。ポルさんも甘えていいってこと？
Yeah. You mean I can be spoiled too?
それはちょっと。
Well, that's...
え？
Huh?
それでは参りましょう。ミオルイでビートイーター！
Well then, let's get started. MioLui with Beat Eater!
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realized now I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't wanna stop, no need
分かってんだ 魅せられたからって
I know you're just showing off
雑な罠にハマるつもりなど無い
and I have no intention of falling for a clumsy trap.
当たり前が止まんない 怖いな
The obvious won't stop, it's scary
もどかしさも正しい命題
Even this frustration is a correct proposition
ハロー 湧いてくる束の間の自負心
Hello, this fleeting sense of pride is welling up
そこからはどう見えてる？
How does it look from over there?
tell me, tell me
どれだけ僕を救ってくれるの
How much will you save me?
反響していく声 加速して
An echoing voice accelerates
始まりは何処から？
Where does it begin?
それも容赦無い力
That too is a merciless power
身体を支配している満ち足りた意欲
A satisfying desire is controlling my body
darlin' darlin' タフに噛んでいくスタイル
darlin' darlin' A style that bites down tough
ままに幕を上げるのさ
Just as it is, the curtain rises
何がどうなったって不思議じゃない
It's not strange no matter what happens
振りを増し答えになって響き出すよ
The moves increase, becoming an answer that echoes out
come over 消えていかない感覚
come over, a feeling that won't disappear
飽くまで踊ってたいだけ
I just want to keep on dancing 'til the end
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realized now I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't wanna stop, no need
やばい何となく なのに
It's bad, somehow, and yet...
見透かされてんの鬼
You see right through me, you demon
予想よりうねって長い傾向
A longer, more winding trend than expected
不確かなものに囲まれてんだね
We're surrounded by uncertain things, aren't we
そこらじゅうに転がってる惰弱
The weak-willed are scattered all over
妄想だって思いのほか重要
Even delusions are more important than you'd think
心に逆らう外れた振る舞い
Behavior that's out of line, against the heart
早まったのさ 引くに引けない様相
I was too hasty, a situation I can't back out of
ほら手に入れた座標を打ち込め
Look, enter the coordinates you've obtained
姿を映してアブラカダブラ
Reflecting the figure, abracadabra
道は分かれてたんだ
Our paths had already diverged
それも遠い所から
From a place far away
全て間違いじゃない悲しみ方
A way of grieving that isn't entirely wrong
darlin' darlin' 満更でもない
darlin' darlin' it's not so bad
ままに塗り直すのさ
Just as it is, I'll paint it over
今になればいつだって構わない
Now, I don't care when it happens
色を変え答えになって溢れ出すよ
The color changes, becoming an answer that overflows
come over 消えていかない感覚
come over, a feeling that won't disappear
消えていかない感覚
A feeling that won't fade
まだまだ足りてないみたい
It seems it's still not enough
重なり合う光 痛みに寄り添う
Overlapping light, I'll stay by the pain
何処にも消えないで欲しい
Please don't disappear anywhere
留まる濃い深い 重心頼り
A deep, lingering, heavy reliance
傷付くこともある
Sometimes I get hurt
darlin' darlin'
タフに噛んでいくスタイル
A style of biting down toughly
まにまに体現するのさ
I'll just embody it as I please
何がどうなったって不思議じゃない
Whatever happens, it's not strange
振りを増し答えになって響き出すよ
The moves increase, becoming the answer and echoing out
come over
消えていかない感覚
A feeling that won't fade
あくまで踊っていたいだけ
I just want to dance, that's all
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realize now, I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばい何となくのに
It's dangerous, I just know it
見透かされてんの鬼
The demon's seeing right through me
続いては鷹嶺ルイで。
Next up is Takane Lui.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, thank you for having me.
よろしくお願いします。
A pleasure.
鷹嶺くんはなんか、うーん、
So, Takane-kun, um...
最近ハマってるゲームとかあるの？
Are there any games you're into lately?
ハマってるゲームあります。
Yes, I do.
あの、最近ってわけでもないんですけど、事務所に入ってからドラゴンクエストというゲームに出会いまして。
Well, it's not that recent, but after joining the agency, I discovered a game called Dragon Quest.
あ、ドラゴンクエスト。
Oh, Dragon Quest.
ああ。
Ah.
ナンバリング1から11までやっていて、
I've played the numbered titles from 1 to 11,
派生とかもあるので、本当に面白くてですね、大好きです。
and there are spin-offs too, so it's really fun. I love it.
その、ドラクエのどんなところが魅力？
So, what about Dragon Quest is so appealing?
魅力たくさんあるんですけど、本当に人生の教科書だなって思うことが結構多くて。
There's a lot to love, but I often think of it as a life textbook.
もちろん悲しいこともあるんですけど、
Of course, there are sad parts too, but...
それを仲間たちと支え合って前に進んでいくパワーとか、
there's the power of supporting each other and moving forward,
ナンバリングが進んでいくにつれて分かる真実とかがあったりとか、
truths that are revealed as you progress through the series,
長年愛されてる理由が集まってるなって感じますね。
I feel it's a collection of reasons why it's been loved for so long.
じゃあ、ゲーム以外も、なんかドラクエのそういうイベントとか行ったりしてるの？
So, aside from the games, do you go to Dragon Quest events?
はい、行ってますね。
Yes, I do.
ドラクエのテーマパークだったりとか、あとは限定ショップに行ったりとか。
Like the Dragon Quest theme park, or going to limited-time shops.
あとはアニメもあるので、あのファンと同時視聴とかしたりしてましたね。はい。
There's also an anime, so I've done watch-alongs with the fans. Yes.
充実してんね。
You're really living it up.
はい。充実してます。
Yes, I'm living it up.
そんなドラクエ大好きな鷹嶺ルイさんには、これからアニメ
For our big Dragon Quest fan, Takane Lui, she will now...
「ドラゴンクエスト ダイの大冒険」の初代オープニング「生きるを する」を披露していただきます。
...perform "Ikiru o Suru," the first opening of "Dragon Quest: The Adventure of Dai."
おお！
Whoa!
それは楽しみだ。
I'm looking forward to that.
楽しみですね。
It's exciting, isn't it?
はい。特別な演出にも注目してくれると嬉しいです。
Yes. I hope you'll pay attention to the special performance, too.
はい。
Okay.
だ、それではスタンバイお願いします。
Alright then, please get ready.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, thank you.
お願いします。
Please do.
いや、ハマれるものがあるっていうのはいいよね。
Yeah, it's great to have something you're really into.
いいですよね。
It really is.
なんやらこの曲を歌ってほしいというリクエストもかなり多かったみたいですよ。
Apparently, there were quite a lot of requests for her to sing this song.
もう、てことはみんな待望ってわけだね。
Oh, so that means everyone's been eagerly waiting.
ですね。
That's right.
だ、それではスタンバイができたみたいなので、行きましょう。
Alright, it seems she's ready, so let's begin.
鷹嶺ルイさんで、
With Takane Lui...
「生きるをする」です。
She will perform 'Ikiru wo Suru.'
どうぞ
Go ahead.
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
Loving myself all the way through.
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, is it still okay to believe?
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter what journey I embark on,
あれ、いつからだ？
Huh, since when?
本音が弱音になったな
Did my true feelings become complaints?
逃げないことが強さになった
Not running away became my strength.
なあ、見つからない？
Hey, can't you find it?
自信じゃなく自分自身
Not confidence, but your own self.
きっとまだ探せてない
I'm sure there are still things I haven't found,
忘れものがあるはず
forgotten things that must exist.
ずっとまだ伝えてない
I still haven't said it,
伝えたい言葉
the words I want to say.
見ててくれるなら魅せてみせるのに
If you're watching, I'll put on a real show for you.
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
Loving myself all the way through.
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, is it still okay to believe?
くすぶるのは、ちゃんと燃えたからだ
The reason it's smoldering is because it burned bright.
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter what journey I embark on,
ただ、目を見開いて
I'll just open my eyes wide
夢を見る
and see the dream.
夢を知る
I'll know the dream.
よう、生きてるかい？
Hey, are you alive?
本当の強さ
True strength is something
きみだけが分かってればいいのさ
only you need to understand.
逃げたり傷ついた
Every time you run away or get hurt,
数だけ居場所は増えたりする
you gain another place where you belong.
見ててくれ
Look at me.
姿じゃなく生き方を
Not my appearance, but the way I live.
僕が僕を愛し抜かなきゃ
I have to love myself all the way through.
終わらない聖者の交信、
The endless communion of saints,
悲しみの縫い目に投げキッス
a blown kiss on the stitches of sorrow.
どこへ向かう旅でも
Whatever journey we head for,
行こうぜ
let's go.
まだ手をとりあって
still holding hands.
脳、映像、スカイはグレー、
Brain, images, the sky is gray,
夜を駆ける
racing through the night.
束の間、終幕、
A brief moment, the final act,
裏切りは愛のおまけ
betrayal is just a bonus gift of love.
かさぶたになる日々
The days that turn into scabs
美しくはないのさ
aren't beautiful, you know.
腰に巻いた正義の切れ味は
The sharpness of the justice I've worn,
どんなだ
what's it like?
僕らは違う痛みを生きる
We live through a different kind of pain
勇敢でいたい、立ち向かいたい
I want to be brave, I want to face it
眠っていたストーリーを
The sleeping story
凄いスピードで覚ましたいや
I want to wake it up at an incredible speed
僕が僕を愛せる強さを
The strength for me to love myself
かなり愛してもいいか？
Is it okay to love you a lot?
くすぶるのだ、燃えカスになるまで
Let it smolder, until it turns to ash
どこへ向かう旅だっていっさいいのさ
It doesn't matter where the journey takes us
ただ、目を見開いて
Just open your eyes
息をする
and breathe.
生きるをする
To live a life
これでも食らえ！
Take this!
続いては、おにかんです。
Next up is Onikan.
よろしくお願いします
Nice to meet you.
前回に引き続き、もう二人は仲がいいね。
Just like last time, you two get along so well.
はい。仲いいですよ。
Yes. We get along well.
あー、息もぴったりだ。
Ah, you're perfectly in sync.
嬢さんは、今日シュークリーム食べた？
Miss Ayame, did you eat a cream puff today?
今日はね、まだ食べてないんですよ。
I haven't eaten one yet today.
でも、お弁当食べました。
But I did eat a bento.
お弁当ね、おいしいのあったからね。
Right, the bento, there was a delicious one.
おいしかったです。
It was delicious.
はい、私たちも後で食べましょうね、ポルさんね。
Yes, let's eat one later too, Polka.
そうだね。お腹ぺこぺこだからね。
That's right. I'm starving.
そうですね。
That's right.
そして何やらお二人は私たちMCに
And it seems you two have something
聞きたいことがあるらしいですよ。
you want to ask us MCs.
はい。
Yes.
何々？
What is it?
いや、こうやってミュージックガーデンやってますけど、
Well, we're doing Music Garden like this, but...
お二人はなんか歌いたいってなってないですか？
don't you two ever feel like singing?
歌いてーみたいな。
Like, "I wanna sing!"
え？
Huh?
歌いてえ
"I wanna sing..."
まあ、多少ね。
Well, a little.
うんふんふん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
口ずさんだり、体を動いたりするけどね、
I might hum along or move my body, but...
でも、MCだから。
I'm the MC, so...
ね、はい、MCなので。
Right, yes, since we're the MCs.
うん。じゃあ、歌って踊りたい
Hmm. So, you want to sing and dance,
っていうことでいいすか？
is that what you mean?
いや、皆さんのいいパフォーマンス見てたらね。
Well, watching everyone's great performances...
うん。じゃあ、ねえ、
Hmm. Well then,
踊って歌いましょうか。
shall we sing and dance?
はい。
Okay.
はい、じゃあ立っていただいて。
Okay, please stand up.
いや、私は。え、いいから立って立って立って。
No, not me. Come on, it's fine, stand up, stand up.
あちら側であの衣装を着替えていただいていいですか。
Could you go over there and change into your outfits?
え。はいはいはい。
Huh? Okay, okay.
すぐ行く、すぐ行く、すぐ行って。
Let's go, let's go, go now.
行ってらっしゃい。
See you later!
はい、じゃあスタンバイしに行ってください。
Okay, please go get ready.
はい。
Okay.
じゃあね、こちらで一旦CMです。
Okay, we'll take a short commercial break.
あ、それ私のセリフ！
Hey, that's my line!
おい、準備できたかな？
Hey, are they ready?
大丈夫かな？着替えて、あ、もうなんかあったんで着替えましたけど。
I wonder. They've changed... oh, they had an outfit and changed.
じゃあね、私たちも行きましょうか。
Well then, shall we go too?
行きましょ、行きましょう。はい。
Let's go, let's go. Okay.
じゃあ、ポルさん、カンペ読んでください。
Okay Polka, please read the cue card.
どうぞ。え？
Here you go. Huh?
それでは聞いてください。
And now, please listen.
おにかんプラスふぶポルでチャンカパーナ。
It's Onikan plus FubuPol with "Chankapana."
深夜バスで君を見た
I saw you on the late-night bus
息を呑むよな黒髪
Your black hair took my breath away
行き先は違うけれど
Our destinations are different,
オレは迷わず飛び乗る
but I jump on without hesitation
一人じゃ悲しすぎる夜さ
The night's too sad to be alone
誰かと話したかった
I wanted to talk to someone
君もうれしそうで
You looked happy too
どちらからともなく 手を握る
and without a word, we held hands
手を握る
holding hands
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapaana, Chankapaana
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so bad it hurts
もう ジンジン 燃えている
I'm already burning up
身体は止まらない
My body won't stop
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapaana, Chankapaana
頷いた君 抱きしめた
You nodded, and I hugged you
恥じらうその瞳 狂ってしまいそう
Those shy eyes might drive me crazy
夜の吐息の中 チャンカパーナ
In the sighs of the night, Chankapaana
チャンカパーナ
Chankapaana
バスを捨てて二人は
We ditched the bus, the two of us,
眠れる場所を探した
and looked for a place to sleep
うやうやしく服を脱ぎ
You reverently take off your clothes
ベッドに滑り込む花
a flower slipping into bed
この世にも天使がいたのさ
So angels do exist in this world
その肌に触れたんだ
I finally got to touch your skin
「恋って好き」なんて悪戯に言うから
You tease, "I like this thing called love,"
舞い上がる
and my heart soars
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapaana, Chankapaana
人生で一番美味しいもの
The tastiest thing in my entire life
そう ナンナン 何度だって
That's right, again and again
君を抱いていたい
I want to hold you
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapaana, Chankapaana
まだまだ君がたりないよ
I still can't get enough of you
露わなその果実
That exposed fruit
狂ってしまいそう
might just drive me crazy
夜よ覚めないでくれ
Oh night, please don't end
チャンカパーナ
Chankapaana
美しい恋にする
I'll make it a beautiful love.
美しい恋にするよ
美しい恋にするから
Because I'll make it a beautiful love...
約束するよ、チャンカパーナ
I promise, Chankapaana.
美しい恋にするから
Because I'll make it a beautiful love
約束するよ、チャンカパーナ
I promise you, Chankapana
月がふたりを探すから
The moon is searching for us
今夜 世界から身を隠そう
So tonight, let's hide from the world
覗いたその肌は褐色の葡萄だね
The skin I peeked at is like a tan grape, isn't it?
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby chan chan chankapana, chankapana
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so much it hurts
もう ジン ジン 燃えている
My tingling body is burning up
身体は止まらない
and it won't stop
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby chan chan chankapana, chankapana
オレの腕にしがみついた
You clung to my arm
華奢なその肩に
Those slender shoulders
狂ってしまいそう
are about to drive me crazy
夜の吐息のなか
In the sighs of the night
チャンカパーナ
Chankapana
(笑)
(Laughs)
鷹嶺ルイ生誕3Dライブを見ている諸君。
To all of you watching the Takane Lui Birthday 3D Live.
お初にお目にかかる。
It is a pleasure to meet you for the first time.
私はゼロ。
I am Zero.
黒の騎士団の総帥にして
Leader of the Black Knights
世界への反逆者。
and a rebel against the world.
ここまでのMがではどうだったかな？
How has the performance been so far?
大いに盛り上がったことだろう。
You must have gotten quite excited.
ほう。だがまだ足りないな。
Hoh. But that's still not enough.
諸君らならまだまだ盛り上がれるはずだ。
You all should be able to get even more excited.
鷹嶺ルイの歌によってな！
Through Takane Lui's song!
ルルーシュ・ヴィ・ブリタニアが命じる！
I, Lelouch vi Britannia, command you!
鷹嶺ルイをコードギアスの主題歌メドレーで
Get even more hyped for Takane Lui
更に盛り上げるのだ！
with this Code Geass theme song medley!
御意、陛下。
Yes, Your Highness.
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
It feels like I could change myself, and even the world.
瞬間は いつもすぐそばに…
That moment is always right beside me...
隠せぬ苛立ちと
With unconcealable irritation,
立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
I stare at myself standing frozen.
迷いながら 悩みながら
While getting lost, while worrying,
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
while regretting, I just have to decide.
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
With the single word you gave me,
戸惑いは消え去り
my hesitation vanished.
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
A light shone into my empty room.
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
The sky I looked up at is clearing into a brilliant blue.
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
I decided to open the window I had closed.
自分を 世界さえも
Myself, and even the world,
変えてしまえそうな
it seems I can change them.
瞬間は
That moment
いつもすぐそばに…
is always right beside me...
夢見てた、夢
The dream I was dreaming,
果て無き遠く
was endlessly far away.
乾いた日々の
Of these dry days,
空色・手の中
the sky color is in my hands.
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Trial and error in the evenly spaced sounds.
時間・間隔の無い空間 ah
A space without time or interval, ah
等身大 音をたてて
Life-sized, making a sound,
僕の顔、造って行く
I create my own face.
キレイに、片方だけ
Beautifully, just one side.
行けどもけものみち
Though I walk this beast's path,
獅子よ虎よと吠え
I roar like a lion and a tiger.
茜射す空の
In the madder-red sky,
彼方にまほろば
beyond lies a paradise.
幽囚の孤獨に
In the loneliness of confinement,
彷徨う青春は
my youth wanders.
弱さと怒りが姿無き敵ですか
Are weakness and anger my formless enemies?
父よ 未だ我は
Father, I am still...
未だ我は
I still
己を知りがたし
find it hard to know myself.
先立つ兄らの
The brothers who go before me,
見えない背中を追えば
I chase their unseen backs.
迷いの一夜に
In a night of wandering,
明星は誘う
the morning star beckons.
死して終わらぬ
Even in death it won't end,
夢を焦がれども
though I yearn for this dream.
確かな君こそ我が命
You are the only one, you are my life.
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
In a wasteland of gales, live as a butterfly, as a flower.
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
An illusion blooming in eternal spring.
混沌の純潔 この身は汚れても
Pure chaos. Though this body may be tainted,
心の錦を信じていてください
please believe in the brocade of my heart.
母よ 決して我は
Mother, I shall never
涙を見せねども
show my tears, but...
足下の草に露は消えもせで
the dew on the grass at my feet will not vanish.
朝も夜も恋い焦がれて
Morning and night, I yearn for you.
星になるよ 君守る
I'll become a star and protect you.
戦いは行く末知らず
The battle's outcome is unknown.
明日と時のวงโคจรを叫んで
Screaming for the orbit of tomorrow and time,
交わらないキミとボク
You and I, who never cross paths.
今行くよ ボクは流れ星
I'm going now. I'm a shooting star.
世界が朽ち果てても
Even if the world rots away,
変わることのないものがある
there are things that never change.
涙をこらえてでも
Even if we hold back our tears,
守るべきものが僕らにはある
we have things we must protect.
何万年何億年前からのメッセージが体内でうずきだす
A message from millions of years ago stirs within me.
鳴り響く
It resounds.
しゃがれた声で 明日を呼ぶ
With a hoarse voice, I call for tomorrow.
傷だらけの手で 君守る
With these scarred hands, I'll protect you.
I continue to fight I continue to fight
見つめ合い 手と手を重ねて
We gaze at each other, our hands overlapping.
ガラス越しのキミとボク
You and I, through the glass.
こんなにも側にいるのに
Even though you're so close to me.
暗い闇を真っ白に染めるよ
I'll dye the deep darkness pure white.
出口のない 君のもとへ
To you, who has no way out.
運命を切り裂く流れ星
A shooting star that tears fate apart.
あふれる君の涙 ボクがいま奪い去る
Your overflowing tears, I'll take them all away now.
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic pieces, one by one,
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
I'll connect them to create a picture.
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
The encounters and farewells you gave me, too.
The meetings and partings you gave me.
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
"This isn't right," I think as I sleep.
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
When I wake, it's the same unchanging, futile cycle.
意味も無く繰り返し
Repeating without meaning.
モザイクカケラ 拾い集めてた
Mosaic pieces I gathered,
「上手く生きる為の術」
"the art of living skillfully."
歪なソレが美しく見えたんだ
those distorted pieces looked beautiful.
強がりながら 躓きながら
Pretending to be strong, while stumbling,
選び抜いた道の上で
on the path I chose.
剥がれ落ちては 埋まらないカケラ
fragments peel off and can't be filled.
はい、ということで特報VTR見ていただきましたけれども、
Alright, so you've just seen the special announcement VTR,
なんとこの鷹嶺ルイ、なんと、なんと、
and guess what, this Takane Lui, what...
コードギアスアンバサダーに決定しました！
I've been appointed as the Code Geass Ambassador!
イエーイ！嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
Yay! I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
もうめちゃくちゃね、コードギアスシリーズだい、だい、大好きなので
I absolutely, truly, truly love the Code Geass series,
こんな素晴らしい機会をいただけるの本当に嬉しいでございます。
so I'm so happy to be given this wonderful opportunity.
皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます。
It's all thanks to you. Thank you so much.
そしてですね、皆さん、お気づき、もう、もう気づいてますよね。
And also, everyone, you've noticed... you've already noticed, right?
もうなんとルルーシュ役の福山さんが
The one and only Fukuyama-san, the voice of Lelouch,
鷹嶺ルイと呼んでいただき、命じていただきました。
called me "Takane Lui" and gave me an order!
本当にすごい。こんな豪華なことってあるんですか。
It's truly amazing. Can something this incredible happen?
いや、本当にありがとうございます。
Wow, thank you so much.
もうコードギアスメドレーでもね、あのバックに、はい、
Also, during the Code Geass medley, in the background, yes,
あのコードギアスのアニメーションも、エンディングと歴代のエンディングとオープニングも流れたということで、
the Code Geass animation, the endings, and the successive openings and endings were shown.
本当に豪華な仕上がりになっていたんですけれども、いかがでしたか、皆さん。
It was a truly spectacular production, but how was it, everyone?
ね、はい。私もめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです。
Right? Yes. I'm also incredibly happy.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
え、アンバサダーとしてのお仕事はですね、
Uh, as for my work as an ambassador,
歌ってみたをあげたりとか、あとは同時視聴をしたりとか、あとはそのほかいろいろ
I've uploaded song covers, held watch-alongs, and various other things.
あの、いろいろ盛りだくさんで用意しておりますので
I have a ton of different things prepared for you.
詳細はですね、この後、え、コードギアスシリーズの公式YouTubeチャンネルにも投稿されますのでぜひぜひチェックしてみてください。
Details will be posted on the official Code Geass series YouTube channel, so please check it out.
もちろん私のXでも、XやYouTubeチャンネルでも、え、詳細をその都度、あの、伝えていきますので、え、チャンネル登録、そしてXのフォローもよろしくお願いします。
Of course, I'll also be sharing details on my X account and YouTube channel, so please subscribe and follow me on X.
さて、この後はですね、新曲を披露させていただきます。
Now then, after this, I will be performing a new song.
よ。
Yo!
来ましたよ。私の新曲が。
It's here! My new song!
ということで新曲のタイトルはですね、ジグザグという曲になっております。ジグザグというのはですね、トラウマの別称になっているんですけれども
So, the title of the new song is "Zig-Zag." "Zig-Zag" is actually another word for trauma.
え、そのジグザグ、え、自分の中にあるトラウマと戦って、前を向いていこうというかっこいい、かっこよく前を向いていくという、え、曲になっておりますので、ぜひぜひ、え、みんなにもちょっと聞いていただいて、あ、こんなことあるな、私もこんなことあるなと共感していただけたら嬉しいなと思います。
This cool song is about fighting your inner trauma and moving forward. I'd be happy if you all listen and can relate, thinking, 'Oh, this happens to me too.'
それではじゃあ曲振りは、え、コードギアスなアンバサダーにもなったということで久々にルイーシュでいきたいと思います。
So then, for the song introduction, since I've become a Code Geass ambassador, I'll do it as "Lui-shu" for the first time in a while.
みんな準備はいいか。あ、私の準備もいいか、大丈夫か。
Everyone, are you ready? Oh, am I ready? Am I okay?
ということで、いきますよ。
Alright then, here we go!
ルイーシュ・ヴィ・タカネリアが命ずる。
I, Lui-shu vi Takaneria, command you.
お前たち、新曲を聴け！
All of you, listen to my new song!
ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー
One, two, three, four.
『幸せ』って囁いた問いがラッタタラッタ
The whispered question of "happiness" goes rattata-ratta.
こびり憑いて離れんわ 駄目だラッタタラッタ
It sticks to me and won't let go, it's no use, rattata-ratta.
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't remember a tasteless, odorless life.
忘れたいから歌った 馬鹿だラッタタラッタ
I sang because I wanted to forget, what a fool, rattata-ratta.
恨む事も 憎む事も 賢くない故 出来なかった
Resenting things, hating things... I wasn't smart enough, so I couldn't do it.
これが君の結末ならば 笑ってしまいたいほど 嘘 嘘 嘘 嘘 嘘
If this is your end, I want to laugh so much. Lie, lie, lie, lie, lie.
「嘘つき」 やだ 痛い痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
"Liar." No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping for a little miracle.
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌！ タチが悪いわ
I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it! You're the worst.
ねえ 辛い Lie Lie Lie Lie 否？ おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, it's painful, Lie Lie Lie Lie, no? Gouge out everything that's strange.
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me heartless, I don't care, call me what you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です ですですです
I want to say bye-bye to this trauma, yes, yes, yes-yes-yes.
私、甘え上手になれなかった
I couldn't be a sweet talker.
可愛げとかが足りなかった
I wasn't cute enough.
後悔が煩い夜だ
A night noisy with regrets.
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば？
Why not just accept the past as the past?
きっといいコトあるさとか
That good things will surely come.
それくらい百も承知だ ラッタッタ
I'm well aware of that much. Rat-tat-tat.
願う事も 祈る事も
Wishing and praying...
許されないから黒く染めた
are not allowed, so I dyed them black.
元の色も思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color.
絡んだ運命の 糸 糸 糸
The tangled threads of fate, thread, thread, thread.
やだ 痛い痛い痛いな
Ugh, it hurts, hurts, hurts.
悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
Acting like the tragic heroine.
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌！諦めちゃえば？
Enough, I hate it, hate it, hate it! Why not just give up?
でも会いたい会いたい会いたいな
But I want to see you, see you, see you.
思考回路がこんがらがっちゃって
My thought process is all tangled up.
明日またきっと壊すけどいいの
I'll surely break it again tomorrow, but that's fine.
トラウマさえ愛おしいのですですで・です
Even the trauma is dear to me, yes, yes, y-yes.
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I'm holding hands with you.
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
Just as we were back then, when we knew nothing.
でもわかっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know that I'll wake up soon.
それならばいっそ君の手でそっと
So then, with your hands, gently...
止め刺して ほら 今 今！
finish me off. Look, now, now!
やだ 痛い痛い痛いな
Ugh, it hurts, hurts, hurts.
奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
Hoping for something like a miracle.
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌！タチが悪いわ
Enough, I hate it, hate it, hate it! This is just awful.
ねえ 辛い Lie Lie Lie 否？
Hey, it's painful, Lie Lie Lie, no?
おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Gouge out all the strange parts.
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
It's fine to be heartless. Call me whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのですですで・です です・です・です
I want to say bye-bye to trauma, yes, yes, y-yes. Yes, yes, yes.
楽しくお届けしてきましたミュージックガーデン、あっという間にエンディングの時間となりました。
We've had fun bringing you Music Garden, and now it's already time for the ending.
ポルさん、今日はどうでしたか？
Polka-san, how was it today?
いや、なんか今日は私も一緒に歌って踊っちゃったからね。
Well, you know, today I ended up singing and dancing along.
いつも以上にボルテージが上がっちゃったね。
My energy was even higher than usual.
あと、もう1時間。
I could go for another hour.
いやいや、やらないですけど、もう、ほんと、もっとやりたいんですけどね。
No, no, we're not, but I'd love to do more.
グッズ販売とプレミア公開も忘れ
Don't forget the merch sales and the premiere...
てますので
so there's something to announce.
ああ、そうかそうか。
Ah, I see, I see.
たかねぇ、今日はてんこ盛りだったね。
Lui, today was jam-packed, wasn't it?
まさか、コードギアスって。
No way... Code Geass.
貯めてる貯めてる。
You're holding back, holding back.
私もね、早く言いたくて言いたくてたまらなかったです。
I've been dying to tell everyone for a while.
この後グッズ販売と新曲プレミア公開、
After this, there will be merchandise sales, a new song premiere,
そしてメンバーシップ限定配信もありますので、
and a members-only stream.
楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです。
I hope you all enjoy it.
本当にこの後も盛りだくさんだ。
There's really a lot more to come.
改めて、お誕生日おめでとうね。
Once again, happy birthday.
ありがとうございまーす。
Thank you so much!
Music Garden 2できて本当に嬉しいです。
I'm so happy we could do Music Garden 2.
ポルさんもふぶさんも本当にありがとうございました。
Polka, Fubuki, thank you so very much.
いえいえ、ありがとうございます。
No, thank you!
まあぜひね、また、またやりたいね。
Yeah, for sure. I want to do this again.
ああ、ぜひまたやりたいですね。
Yeah, I'd love to do it again.
よろしくお願いします。
Let's do it.
さ、せっかくですので、ゲストの皆さんにも感想いただきましょう。
Alright, since we have the chance, let's hear from our guests.
皆さんから何か言いたいことがあるみたいですよ。
It seems they have something they want to say.
おお。
Ooh.
るいー！
Lui!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
わー！やったー！
Waaah! Yay!
ありがとうございます！みんなと歌えて幸せでした。
Thank you! I was so happy to sing with everyone.
またコラボしよう。
Let's collab again.
ぜひ！したい！したい！
Definitely! Let's do it!
はい、では本当あっという間ですが、
Yes, time really flew by, but...
今夜のMusic Gardenはここまでとなります。
that's all for tonight's Music Garden.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
それではまたMusic Garden 3が叶う日まで、さようなら。
Well then, until the day Music Garden 3 comes true, goodbye.
さようなら。
Goodbye.
さようならー。
Goodbye!
さようならー！
ラプ、やべぇぞ。
La+, this is insane.
どうしたの？
What is it?
とんでもねぇグッズ出るぞ。
Some incredible merch is coming out.
はい？
Huh?
バカすげぇグッズが一気に来るぞ。
A ton of ridiculously awesome merch is coming all at once.
Tシャツ。
A T-shirt.
おお。
Ooh.
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド。
A glitter acrylic stand.
おつ。
Nice.
ゆるかわバケットハット。
A cute, laid-back bucket hat.
ほしい！
I want it!
ロック風パーカー。
A rock-style hoodie.
着たい！
I wanna wear it!
そしてフルセットには直筆サイン入りポストカードが付くぞ。
And the full set comes with a personally signed postcard!
のどちんてー！
I'm dying for it!
さらにホロカもついてくる。
Plus, it comes with a holo-card.
うおー！
Woooah!
これは買いでしょう。
You've gotta buy this.